Michael Groves

michaeliangroves@gmail.com 07915269204

Github LinkedIn Codewars

About Me

I am a Software Developer/Consultant living in Shropshire. Now with a years professional experience under my belt working as a Software Consultant for Capgemini SE, I am keen to start the next phase of my career and have an eye on accelerating my individual growth and furthering the knowledge and experience I have thus far attained. I am looking for an exciting new opportunity with a company that champions innovation and supports ambitious and creative engineers.

I have also spent many years working in the financial sector as a Collections Executive and AR Officer.

Skills

Problem Solving

During my time spent as an Audio Engineer and Music Producer I developed a very keen eye for recognising problems early and finding solutions fast. This was then carried over into my work in Accounts where my eye for detail and experience with identifying problems left me in a good position at McLean Delmo Bentleys. As their principal Collections Executive I streamlined and modernised their method of reporting aged client debt. I have found my commitment to this skill in particular has been a considerable advantage for me whilst working as a software developer.

Communication/Diplomacy

Through my commitment to transparency and unique experience working with individuals from the financial world and the arts, I have cultivated a consistent ability to develop solid and lasting client relationships and a solid reputation for being someone people can rely on for honest and constructive contributions to my team. During my time working for McLean Delmo Bentleys I had the difficult task of managing targets set by the CFO to collect aged debt whilst ensuring partner client relationships at the firm remained strong. This resulted in being placed often in the middle of any disputes and required a firm but open approach to diplomacy in resolving any conflicts.

Process

Agile Processes

A firm commitment to Test Driven Development.

CI/CD Pipeline and DevOps. Project Planning: user stories, database structure and relationships, mock-ups. Team Processes: pairing, mobbing, retros, check-ins. Solid commitment to industry-standard best practices ensuring clean, efficient, readable code (Single Responsibility, DRY).

Public Speaking

I have always found public speaking to be something which came naturally to me, and which lead me to a brief stint in Theatre where I performed as the lead in a production of 'Hair' at the London Palladium. My time working as a vocalist in a touring band has also allowed me to further strengthen my confidence and ability to speak clearly and to engage with large groups of people.

Education

Makers Academy (August 2020 - October 2020)

Applying industry-standard practices:

Object Oriented Programming, Test Driven Development, Behavioural Driven Development with testing frameworks: RSpec, Jasmine, Jest, JUnit

Learning skills to become programming language agnostic using:

Java, Ruby, Javascript, NodeJS, React, HTML5/CSS

User Stories

Domain Modeling:

CRC, UML, Wireframes

Linting, code quality, test coverage with rubocop, simplecov

Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment/Continuous Delivery

CI/CD pipeline with TravisCI and Heroku

Agile Processes

(~2 week) group projects, Trello, "Minimum Viable Product (MVP), pairing in 2-day sprints, stand-ups, mood check-ins and retros

Chartered Insurance Institute - UK financial services, regulation & ethics (93%)

University of Sussex (2011 - 2013)

BA(hons) - Music 2.2

Experience

Capgemini SE - Telford Office (August 2021 - Present)

I currently work as a contractor for Capgemini on HMRC projects. Some of my achievements and responsibilities include:

- Building well tested microservices using Java, Spring Boot and Hibernate.
- · Used OpenApi to deliver RESTful APIs.
- Persued and encouraged TDD with every project and within every team.
- Defined and refined package structures for the individual microservices. Refactored code and made improvements continuously where necessary.
- Built and maintained a Gitlab CI/CD pipeline with multiple stages.
- Given sole ownership on a new project developing a microservice from end to end using all of the tools and knowledge I acquired.
- Supported the projects through a full software development lifecycle.
- Learned PLSQL on the fly to successfully build an anonymous block for communicating with a Stored Procedure built by database engineers on the project.
- Worked with agile methodologies within my team.
- As per request of the management, 'buddied' with and brought up to speed another existing staff member who they had felt was getting left behind on a project.

Technologies and Methodologies Used - - Open API · Mockito · JUnit · Spring Cloud · Docker · Gitlab · Oracle Database · Maven · IntelliJ IDEA · DevOps · Hibernate · Java Database Connectivity (JDBC) · Postman · Java · Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) · Kubernetes · Spring Boot · Test Driven Development

McLean Delmo Bentleys - Melbourne Office (December 2019 - March 2020)

Collections Executive

- Journals and multi-currency inter-company journals.
- Debtor management for 11 company partners, writing databases and use of standard Excel macros, Vlookups and pivot tables.
- Using adequate measures to encourage payments before escalating to debt collections.
- · CFO and partner relationship management.
- Preparing meaningful, accurate and timely monthly management reports.

British and Irish Institute for Modern Music (June 2018 – October 2019)

AR and Student Finance Advisor

Freelance Song-Writer and Producer

Contract with Altitude Music London (August 2015 - February 2018)

Paul Godfrey - Morcheeba (2015)

Audio Engineer and Session Musician (February 2012 – November 2016)

inc. Yonaka/Morcheeba/Miamigo/KINS/The Confidentials

Hobbies & Other Interests

The pub is often where you will find me, engaging in conversation with friends and enjoying a few gins. I am a keen reader, enjoying such subjects as Economics, Philosophy, and Political Theory. I also love science fiction and fantasy novels. Strategy games (chess, computer games)

I still occasionally write music and enjoy production and sound design.